MARCO ANTONIO DE JESUS CIRIACO

Veracruz 635, El Mante, 45235 Zapopan, Jal. | 477 321 28 20 | marco_dejesus@live.com

PROFILE

3 years of experience as Manual Software Tester, Able to Lead a System Integration Testing Project Team during many different Test Cycles with up to 15 Team members. Experienced on Manual Testing Types (E2E Testing, Core Functional Testing, DB Testing, Usability Testing, Regression Testing, Cross Browser Testing, Accessibility Testing, and System Integration Testing); Overall understanding of Software Development Life Cycle as a base for Software Testing Life Cycle implementation, Defect Management, Defect Lifecycle, Lean IT, Page Object Pattern for Automation Testing, Healthcare Vertical Knowledge, Service Virtualization.

2 years of experience as Java Developer in Core Java for Web Applications (JSP) and web technologies such as JSON, JQuery, Ajax, xHTML and CSS styling. Experienced with Tomcat Server and Xampp stack for PHP development; Able to work with **Three Layer Applications** (Data Layer, Business Layer and Presentation Layer) with JPA; Experienced on Triggers, Stored Procedures and Functions as well as Nested Queries in regards of DRMS.

EDUCATION

Universidad de la Salle Bajio Campus Campestre. Leon, Guanajuato.

Master Degree in Administrative Engineering and Quality May 2015

Universidad Tecnologica de Leon. Leon, Guanajuato.

Bachelor's Degree on Information Technologies Engineer April 2012

Universidad Tecnologica de Leon. Leon, Guanajuato.

Technical Degree on Computer Systems April 2010

Universidad de la Salle Bajio Campus Campestre Leon, Guanajuato.

Diploma in Software Development (.NET Framework 3.5)

June 2010

TRAINING

Automated Testing Framework with Selenium (Plural Sight)	January 2016
Automated Web Testing with Selenium (Plural Sight)	August 2015
ISTQB Training for ISTQB Foundational Level Certification	May 2015
Automation Training in RFT	February 2015
Multi Browser Compatibility Testing	March 2014
Web Accessibility Testing and Tools Training	April 2013
Software Testing Lifecycle	January 2013
V-Model Training	January 2013
Defect Lifecycle Training	January 2013
SDLC Training	December 2012
Software Development Diploma in .NET Framework 3.5	June 2010
Three Layer Architecture in VB NET	June 2010

Technical Skills

Quality Tools

Lean Concepts, Waste Elimination, Muda, 7/8 wastes, Value Steam Mapping, Cycle Time Reduction, Continuous Flow, Kanban, 5S, Standard Work, Poka yoke, Kaizen, TPM, Visual Control, Statistical Quality Control.

Testing Tools

Selenium Web Driver, Team Foundation Server, Rational Clear Quest, Rational Requisite Pro, Rational Quality Manager, Total Validator Tool, Juicy Studio, Chrome Vox Screen Reader, SharePoint 2010, Excel Macros Development, CA Lisa, iMac OS Installation and configuration. Command line handling, SOAP UI

Application Servers, IDEs, Build and integration tools

Eclipse, SVN, NetBeans, MS SQL Management Studio, MySQL Workbench

OS and DB Manager System

Apache Server, Tomcat, Xampp, Unix-like systems (Ubuntu, Fedora, iMac), MySQL, MS SQL Server 2005

Software Methodologies and others

Scrum, SOAP UI, JSF, JDBC, XML

RELATED EXPERIENCE

Softtek

Senior QA Analyst June 2015 – Current

Ensure Web Application Changes are merged to Production environment with Zero or at least with minimal minor defects through Scrum Methodology. Make sure User Stories are delivered as per Sprint planning and schedule.

UST Global

Tester November 2012 – June 2015

Make sure that Defects are identified for System Changes Requests following the Software Testing Lifecycle in a V-Model

Universidad Tecnologica de Leon

Java Developer May 2011 – May 2012

Development of web applications with java technologies

Project Administration

Reports Creation

Support of various departments within the University

Process Flow Modeling

Requirements Gatherings

Smar Yeo Consultores TI (Software Development Consulting)

PHP Developer March 2010 – November 2010

Websites Development with PHP and Action Script

Functional testing

User and Technical Manuals Creation

Teletech

Customer Service Representative

January 2009 - March 2009

Customer service in English/Spanish for Sprint-Nextel campaign Tech Support and Radio Solutions Billing Service Support

LANGUAGES

Spanish – Native English – Speak, Read, and Write. Advanced

ASPIRATIONS AND EXPECTATIONS

Following my Career Path will brand me as a very Strong Associate for a company in Quality and Processes Improvement, becoming an essential advisor, leading the company to grow and to exploit the Core potential Resources.

I'm expecting to work with people from different countries in order to know their way of work, culture and gather knowledge from their experience. This will allow me to improve my English communications skills or other language needed.